ถัดไปจะเป็นหัวข้อพิเศษนะคะจากทางสปอนเซอร์ที่น่ารักของเราอีกหนึ่งท่านนะคะ
ก็คือ ExxonMobil ค่ะ
นะคะวันนี้มากับหัวข้อที่มีชื่อว่า We Are ExxonMobil นะคะ
โดยที่วันนี้ค่ะ เราได้รับเกียรติจากคุณสุวิชา แก้วละเอียดนะคะ
เป็น IT Solution Architect จาก ExxonMobil
จะมาพูดคุยกับเราด้านบนเวที
เดี๋ยวรอสักครู่เดียวนะคะ
So please stay tuned, ladies and gentlemen,
for this special section, our one of our
beloved partner which is ExxonMobil.
By คุณสุวิชา แก้วละเอียดค่ะ
He is the IT Solution Architect from ExxonMobil.
He's going to talk on the topic of We Are ExxonMobil.
So please stay tuned.
ก็ตอนนี้นะคะ ท่านไหนที่ยังไม่ได้รับของที่ระลึกนะคะ
เรามีของที่ระลึกแจกด้วย
ทุกท่านเลยที่ลงทะเบียนมาร่วมงานกับเรา
ก็จะได้รับของที่ระลึกฟรีไปนะคะ
หลังจากที่ออกจากห้องแล้ว ก่อนจะกลับบ้าน
ไปเจอกันได้ที่ชั้น 7 นะคะ
ก็จะมีพี่ๆ ที่เค้าอยู่ตรงจุดแจกของที่ระลึกนะคะ
ก็ยื่นตัวป้ายชื่อนะคะ
แล้วก็เจ้าหน้าที่จะมอบของที่ระลึกให้
แต่ว่าวันนี้เนี่ยพอเสร็จแล้วก็อย่าเพิ่งไปไหน
เพราะว่าเราต้อง work-life balance นะคะ
ก็ปาร์ตี้กันต่อเลยนะคะ
มีเป็นช่วง networking ปาร์ตี้นะคะ
ก็จะมีดีเจ มีอาหาร
แล้วก็คือรับประทานอาหารเย็นด้วยกันได้เลย
แล้วก็มีเครื่องดื่ม มีเบียร์เสิร์ฟตลอดทั้งงานนะคะ
อันนี้ฟรีนะคะ เรียนเชิญนะคะที่ชั้น 7
ซึ่งเราจะต่อเลยจากพอจบ Q&A บนเวทีแล้วเนี่ย
เดี๋ยวเราจะย้ายไปชั้น 7 กัน
ก็เรียนเชิญทุกท่านนะคะ
ท่านไหนไม่ติดธุระไปที่ไหนก็อยู่ปาร์ตี้ด้วยกันก่อน
เพราะว่าอยู่ที่นี่เนี่ย งานของเรานะคะ
ก็มาจากหลาย community ด้วยกันนะคะ
ตอนนี้คุณสุวิชาพร้อมแล้วค่ะ
ขอเสียงปรบมือต้อนรับคุณสุวิชา แก้วละเอียดค่ะ
IT Solution Architect จาก ExxonMobil
ขอบคุณมากครับ สวัสดีครับทุกคน
หน้ามาเยอะทีเดียวนะฮะ จาก ExxonMobil ครับ พี่น้องกัน
Good afternoon, everybody.
I hope you enjoy the session so far and got what you
expected to learn today.
Since our company is quite new in the software
development community.
So that's why I have only one slide here.
Just for you to absorb the logos and the taglines here.
And in the future, we hope we will be partner with the
software development community again.
Today, I like to have these five minutes to talk about
our company.
And I hope that at the end of the session, you will
learn more who we are.
And hopefully, you will know why we are here.
So our company is actually from US.
The headquarter is in Irving, Texas in the US states.
And we have around 70,000 employees around the world,
which is very big.
And we are the global company, have affiliates around
the world.
And our business is actually the integrated oil and gas
company.
Which is actually the company that have the process
end-to-end.
Starting from the exploration to find the new natural
resources around the world.
And then do the development, which is the drilling to
get some stuff up.
And then production, which is mainly refinery and
manufacturing of the end products that you consume
nowadays, which is fuels, lubes, and chemicals.
Now, talking about the IT department in our company,
it is a big company.
And as you can imagine now, IT and the business cannot
be departed in many companies.
So that's why ExxonMobil IT has the center in Thailand
as well.
And Thailand is one of the biggest IT centers that
operate to help the business client and also the
customer of ExxonMobil company around the world.
Now, imagine if in Thailand, we have around 2,500
employees.
And out of those, we have 500 as the IT people.
Employees and out of 500 we have around nowadays
100 people working as developer roles.
So it is quite big so the developer will have a chance
to support the business client users within the company
and also external customer around the world
and within Thailand as well.
Alright so this is who we are as the developer
within ExxonMobil.
But then I think you may want to know in details
how is the life of the developers in ExxonMobil, right?
So I like for you to remember three things.
The first one is global business centers.
As you can imagine we are the global company.
So that's why our developers will support
the business user around the world,
have a chance to use their English,
and have the soft skills to talk to the business people,
the customer, the clients around the world
with different cultures, right?
And also a big opportunity for the developers
to have a business trip to travel to talk with them
face-to-face in order to find the best solution
for the business.
So that is the first one.
The second thing that I want you to remember about us is
we are expecting the long-term career for the developers
within our company.
Why we want to do that, right?
The company I think one of the philosophy of the company
is that we want the long-term employee because we think
that the people is the most important aspects
or resources within the company, right?
So that's why we want to develop and we look at developer
as one of the key role that we want to grow
within the company because nowadays developer is the one
who can make changes within the company.
And the last one which is number three
and this is the important thing nowadays
is digital transformation.
ExxonMobil has invested a lot in IT since the past.
In the past we may end up buying the enterprise
or vendor products, right?
But nowadays with the business want to scale
and have the agility to do the business,
we want the IT to be able to scale and have
the modularized aspect within the architecture
of the whole IT solution in the company.
So that's why developer is playing
the very important role here in order to deliver that
to the business, right?
And have the business success in the market.
So that's it.
So I hope ExxonMobil will be the venue
for the developers in Thailand because I'm proud to say
that actually we have Thai people, right?
Sitting in Houston talking to the business stakeholder,
like the leaders of the company in order to drive
the IT solution that we think is the best
for the company, right?
So we are proud of that.
So I hope that it will be the venue for you as a choice
to ปล่อยของ right?
And we have a lot of tools technology
that we have in the company.
So if you like to ปล่อยของ and also earn
and develop yourself so you can come to join us.
That's it.
That's what we are and we are ExxonMobil.
Thank you.
ค่ะ ขอบคุณค่ะคุณสุวิชา
We are ExxonMobil นะคะ
เผื่อท่านไหนสนใจนะคะ
อย่าลืมมาสมัครงานกับ ExxonMobil นะคะ
คุณจะได้ปล่อยของไปพร้อมๆ กัน
ดิฉันก็สงสัยเหมือนกันคำว่าปล่อยของภาษาอังกฤษคืออะไร
มีใครทราบมั้ยคะ
โอ มีคำตอบเต็มเลย
เดี๋ยวขออนุญาต มีท่านไหนทราบมั้ยคะ
เออ อันนี้เดี๋ยวหนูขออนุญาตไป search Google ก่อนนะคะ
อ้า น่าสนใจค่ะ ไม่เคยคิดถึงคำนี้มาก่อนนะคะ